Guide to the Karl Menger Papers, 1872-2000 RL.00888
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence Series, 1918-1984; 1
  - Unidentified correspondents, 1921-1982 and undated; 3 folders (Box 4)
    Topic(s): Unidentified correspondents, 3 folders: 1921-1949; 1950-1982; undated
  - Veblen, Oswald, 1930-1942 (Box 5)
    Topic(s): Routine exchange; business exchange
  - Ville, Jean André, 1935-1951 (Box 5)
  - General correspondence, "V", 1936-1960 (Box 5)
    Other correspondents with last name beginning with V.
  - Waerden, Bartel Leendart van der, 1929-1965 (Box 5)
    Dutch mathematician and historian of mathematics. Some outgoing correspondence.
    Topic(s): Routine exchanges; business exchange
  - Wald, Abraham, 1932-1938 and undated (Box 5)
    Austro-Hungarian mathematician, decision theorist, econometrician, and geometer; member of Menger's Mathematical Colloquium.
    Topic(s): Metric geometry; comments on papers; routine exchange; exchange about the Mathematical Colloquium; miscellaneous mathematical discussions
  - Werba, Helmut, 1980-1981 and undated (Box 5)
    Austrian philosopher. Some outgoing correspondence.
    Topic(s): Exchange about a possible German publication of Menger's early writings on mathematics and philosophy
  - Whyburn, Gordon Thomas, 1928-1937 and undated (Box 5)
    Topic(s): Comments on papers; routine exchange
  - Wieser, Friedrich von, 1921 (Box 5)
    Austrian economist.
    Topic(s): Carl Menger's death
  - General correspondence, "W", 1926-1980 and undated (Box 5)
    Other correspondents with last name beginning with W. Some outgoing correspondence.
  - General correspondence, "Y", 1948-1949 (Box 5)
    Other correspondents with last name beginning with Y.
  - Zellweger, Shea, 1976-1983 and undated (Box 5)
    American psychologist and logician. Some outgoing correspondence.
    Topic(s): Copy of Piaget (1952); comments on papers; mathematical discussions
  - Zippin, Leo, 1930 and undated (Box 5)
    Topic(s): Routine exchange; mathematical discussions
  - Zygmund, Antoni, 1952-1965 and undated (Box 5)
    Polish mathematician; some outgoing correspondence
    Topic(s): Routine exchange; comments on Menger's book "Calculus"
  - General correspondence, "Z", 1929-1964 (Box 5)
    Other correspondents with last name beginning with Z.
- Writings and Research Series, 1921-1983 and undated; 2
  The Writings and Research Series includes drafts, proofs, notes, and published copies of Menger's books, articles, speeches, and other works, spanning his entire career. Files in each subseries are arranged chronologically by publication date.
  Materials are written in German and English. Menger also used both German and English shorthand for his notes and writings, making translations difficult. A significant amount of unsorted material, largely consisting of loose pages with unidentified topics and writings, is filed in the Drafts and Proofs Subseries. Additionally, the Notebooks and Notes Series has a significant amount of material related to Menger's Writings and Research Series.
  - Books, 1
    - Kurventheorie, 1932 (Box 6)
      Incomplete
    - Moral, Wille und Weltgestaltung, 1934 (Box 6)
    - Untitled (General Book on Mathematics), 1935/36; 3 folders (Box 6)
      Draft, unpublished
    - Three Lectures on Mathematical Subjects, 1940 (Box 6)
    - Algebra of Analysis, 1944 (Box 6)
    - The Concept of a Function, 1948-1949 (Box 6)
      1st ed. (1948) and 2nd ed. (1949)
    - Introduction to Calculus. Part I, 1950 (Box 7)
    - Understanding Calculus. Part I, 1950 (Box 7)
      Includes German draft (handwritten)
    - Understanding Calculus. Part II, 1950 (Box 7)
    - You Will Like Geometry. A Guide Book for the lllinois Institute of Technology Geometry Exhibition at the Museum of Science and Industry, 1952-1961 (Box 7)
      First printing (1952) and third printing (1961); incl. a magazine article about the exhibition with a photograph of Karl Menger; incl. draft titled "A Geometric Exhibition"
    - Calculus. A Modern Approach, 1952; 4 folders (Box 7)
      Includes draft
    - Calculus. A Modern Approach, 2nd ed., 1953; 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Géométrie Générale, 1954 (Box 8)
    - Calculus. A Modern Approach, 1955 (Box 8)
      Draft, incomplete:; incl. "Remarks concerning my book Calculus"
    - The Basic Concepts of Mathematics. A Companion to Current Textbooks on Algebra and Analytic Geometry. Part I. Algebra, 1956; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - The Basic Concepts of Mathematics. A Companion to Current Textbooks on Algebra and Analytic Geometry. Part I. Algebra, 1957; 2 folders (Box 27)
      2nd edition
    - Calculus. The Elements. Introduction into Pre-Limit Calculus for Everyone, Chapter I + II, 1966-1967; 2 folders (Box 27)
      Chapter I (1966) and Chapter II (1967); incl. copies with comments (Chapter I) and draft of Chapter II
    - Morality, Decision and Social Organization, 1974 (Box 27)
      1st and 2nd proof, draft
    - Selected Papers in Logic and Foundations, Didactics, Economics, 1979 (Box 27)
      Incomplete; incl. draft and comments
    - Reminiscences of the Vienna Circle and Mathematical Colloquium, Ch. I-III, 1994 and undated; 5 folders (Box 9)
      Drafts, edits
    - Reminiscences of the Vienna Circle and Mathematical Colloquium, Ch. IV-XI, 1994 and undated; 9 folders (Box 10)
    - Reminiscences of the Vienna Circle and Mathematical Colloquium, Ch. XII--XVI, Memoires of Kurt Gödel, Miscellaneous and unidentified material, 1994 and undated; 8 folders (Box 11)
    - Biography of Carl Menger, undated; 10 folders (Box 28)
      Drafts
  - Essays and Articles, 2
    - Der Economist: Lebensmittelzuschüsse und Noteninflation, 1921 (Box 12)
      Published in "Neue Freie Presse," Vienna on November 17, 1921)
    - Zur Dimensions- und Kurventheorie. Unveröffentlichte Aufsätze aus den Jahren 1921-1923 (Box 12)
      Published in 1929, incl. draft
    - Über die DimensionaIität von Punktmengen, I. Teil, 1923 (Box 12)
    - Einige Überdeckungssätze der PunktmengenIehre, 1924 (Box 12)
    - Über die Dimension von Punktmengen, 1924 (Box 12)
      Includes handwritten draft
    - Über die Dimension von Punktmengen, II. Teil, 1924 (Box 12)
      Includes copy of handwritten draft
    - Grundzüge einer Theorie der Kurven, 1925 (Box 12)
      Includes copy with comments
    - Allgemeine Räume und Cartesische Raume I, II, 1926 (Box 12)
    - Bericht über die Dimensionstheorie, 1926 (Box 12)
    - Dimensionstheoretische Konsequenzen des Verhältnisses von allgemeinen Räumen und Zahlenräumen, 1926 (Box 12)
    - Über geodätische Linien in allgemeinen metrischen Räumen, 1926 (Box 12)
    - Über reguläre Baumkurven, 1926 (Box 12)
    - Zur allgemeinen Kurventheorie, 1926 (Box 12)
    - Zur Entstehung meiner Arbeiten über Dimensions- und Kurventheorie, 1926 (Box 12)
    - Bemerkungen zur zweiten Untersuchung über allgemeine Metrik, 1927 (Box 12)
    - Das Hauptproblem über die dimensionelle Struktur der Räume, 1927 (Box 12)
    - Die Haupttheoreme der Dimensionstheorie, 1927 (Box 12)
    - Zusammenhangsstufen und Cantorsche Mannigfaltigkeiten, 1927 (Box 12)
    - Bemerkungen zu Grundlagenfragen I-IV, 1928 (Box 12)
    - Der allgemeine Trennungssatz, 1928 (Box 12)
    - Die Metrik des Hilbertschen Raumes, 1928 (Box 12)
    - Die Halbstetigkeit der Bogenlänge, 1928 (Box 12)
    - Dimension und Zusammenhangsstufe, 1928 (Box 12)
      With W. Hurewicz
    - Dimensionstheoretische Notizen IV, 1928 (Box 12)
    - Ein Theorem der Topologie, Dimensionstheoretische Notizen I-III, 1928 (Box 12)
      Two articles
    - Ein Theorem über die Bogenlänge, 1928 (Box 12)
    - Metrische Untersuchungen, 1928 (Box 12)
    - Notizen zur Konvexitätstheorie, 1928 (Box 12)
    - Untersuchungen über allgemeine Metrik I-III, 1928; 2 folders (Box 12)
      Includes comments and inserts
    - Die allgemeine Kurventheorie, 1929 (Box 12)
    - Allgemeine Räume und Cartesische Räume III. Beweis des Fundamentalsatzes, 1929 (Box 12)
    - Antwort auf eine Note von Brouwer, 1929; 1 folders (Oversize-box 1)
    - Dimensionstheoretische Notizen, 1929 (Box 12)
      Ein Zerlegungssatz für rational- und irrational-dimensionale Mengen; Über die nirgends dichten Teilmengen des Rn; Über die Summe regulärer Kurven
    - Über die Dimension von Punktmengen III. Zur Begründung einer axiomatischen Theorie der Dimension, 1929 (Box 12)
    - Über eine neue Definition der Bogenlänge. Eine weitere Verallgemeinerung des Längenbegriffes, 1929 (Box 12)
    - Über die Summe regulärer Kurven, 1929 (Box 12)
    - Zur Begründung einer axiomatischen Theorie der Dimension, 1929 (Box 12)
    - Antwort auf eine Note von Brouwer, 1930 (Box 13)
    - Axiomatische Einführung des Dimensionsbegriffes, 1930 (Box 13)
    - Bemerkungen über dimensionelle Feinstruktur und Produktsatz, 1930 (Box 13)
    - Der Intuitionismus, 1930 (Box 13)
    - Eine dimensionstheoretische Bemerkung von O. Schreier, 1930 (Box 13)
    - Einführung des Komplexes in die allgemeine Metrik, 1930 (Box 13)
    - Entwurf einer neuen Theorie des Maßes, 1930 (Box 13)
    - Otto Schreier. Nachruf, 1930 (Box 13)
      Obituary
    - Remarques sur la theorie axiomatique de la dimension, 1930 (Box 13)
      With C. Kuratowski
    - Über den n-Beisatz in lokal-zusammenhängenden Kontinua, 1930 (Box 13)
      With Georg Nöbeling
    - Über die sogenannte Konstruktivität bei arithmetischen Definitionen, 1930 (Box 13)
    - Über einen Abstandsbegriff in Gruppen, 1930 (Box 13)
    - Über plättbare Dreiergraphen und Potenzen nichtplättbarer Graphen, 1930 (Box 13)
    - Untersuchungen über allgemeine Metrik Teil IV: Zur Metrik der Kurven, 1930 (Box 13)
    - Beiträge zur Gruppentheorie I. Über eine Gruppenmetrik, 1931 (Box 13)
    - Bericht über ein mathematisches Kolloquium 1929/30, 1931 (Box 13)
    - Bericht über metrische Geometrie, 1931 (Box 13)
    - Ein Problem von Blaschke, 1931 (Box 13)
    - Eine neue Kennzeichnung der Geraden, 1931 (Box 13)
    - New Foundations of Euclidian Geometry, 1931 (Box 13)
    - Remarks Concerning the Paper of W. L. Ayres on the Regular Points of a Continuum, 1931 (Box 13)
    - Some Applications of Point Set Methods, 1931 (Box 13)
    - Über den Konstruktivitätsbegriff. Zweite Mitteilung, 1931 (Box 13)
    - Eine Zuschrift von Karl Menger an Hans Hahn betreffend Mengers Antwort auf eine Note von Brouwer, 1932 (Box 13)
    - Neuere Methoden und Probleme der Geometrie, 1932 (Box 13)
    - Über die Hinweise auf Brouwer in Urysohns Memoire, 1932 (Box 13)
    - Die neue Logik, 1933 (Box 13)
    - Über den imaginären euklidischen Raum, 1933 (Box 13)
    - Vorwort und Nachwort zu: Fünf Wiener Vorträgen (Krise und Neuaufbau in den exakten Wissenschaften, Alte Probleme - Neue Lösungen in den exakten Wissenschaften), 1933-1934 (Box 13)
      Preface and epilogue
    - Bericht über neueste Ergebnisse der metrischen Geometrie, 1934 (Box 13)
    - Bemerkungen zu: Das Unsicherheitsmoment in der Wertlehre, 1934 (Box 13)
    - Das Unsicherheitsmoment in der Wertlehre. Betrachtungen in Anschluß an das sogenannte Petersburger Spiel, 1934 (Box 13)
      Includes printed and early handwritten drafts
    - Ist die Quadratur des Kreises lösbar?, 1934 (Box 13)
    - Hans Hahn, 1935 (Box 13)
    - Hans Hahn, 1935 (Box 13)
    - Metrische Geometrie und Variationsrechnung, 1935 (Box 13)
    - Sull Indirizzo di Idee e sulle Tendenze Principali dei Colloquio Matematico di Vienna, 1935 (Box 13)
    - Sur un théorème général du calcul des variations, 1935 (Box 13)
      Includes comments
    - Bemerkungen zu den Ertragsgesetzen, 1936 (Box 13)
    - Calcul des variations dans les espaces distanciés généraux, 1936 (Box 13)
    - Courbes minirnisantes non-rectifiables et champs généraux des courbes admissibles dans le calcul des variations, 1936 (Box 13)
    - Einige neuere Fortschritte in der exakten Behandlung sozialwissenschaftlicher Probleme, 1936 (Box 13)
    - Metric Methods in Calculus of Variations, 1936 (Box 13)
    - New Foundations of Projective and Affine Geometry, 1936 (Box 13)
      With F. Alt and O. Schreiber
    - New Ways in Differential Geometry, 1936 (Box 13)
    - Vorwort zu: Friedrich Waismann; Einführung in das mathematische Denken, 1936 (Box 13)
      Preface
    - Weitere Bemerkungen zu den Ertragsgesetzen, 1936 (Box 13)
    - A Note on a Previous Paper "New Foundations of Projective and Affine Geometry", 1937 (Box 14)
      With Franz Alt
    - An Exact Theory of Social Relations and Groups, 1937 (Box 14)
    - Die metrische Methode in der Variationsrechnung, 1937 (Box 14)
    - La géométrie des distances et ses relations avec les autres branches des mathématiques, 1937 (Box 14)
    - Metric Methods in Calculus of Variations, 1937 (Box 14)
    - Nouvelle démonstration de l'équation d'Euler-Lagrange, 1937 (Box 14)
      Marked as "incorrect", présentée par M. Élie Cartain
    - The New Logic, 1937 (Box 14)
    - What Is the Calculus of Variations and What Are Its Applications?, 1937 (Box 14)
    - A Foundation of Projective Geometry, 1938 (Box 14)
    - A New Foundation of Non-Euclidean, 1938 (Box 14)
    - A Symposium on the Algebra of Geometry and Related Subjects, 1938 (Box 14)
    - An Abstract Form of the Covering Theorems of Topology, 1938 (Box 14)
    - An Exact Theory of Social Groups and Relations, 1938 (Box 14)
    - Axiomatique simplifiée de l'algèbre de la géométrie projective, 1938 (Box 14)
    - Introduction to: L. M. BlumenthaI; Distance Geometries, 1938 (Box 14)
    - Non-Euclidean Geometry of Joining and Intersecting, 1938 (Box 14)
    - Nouvelle base pour le développement de la géométrie de Bolyai et Lobatchefski, 1938 (Box 14)
      Includes drafts with Helen Skala with comments
    - Une forme abstraite du théorème de Borel-Lebesgue généralisé, 1938 (Box 14)
    - A Logic of the Doubtful. On Optative and Imperative Logic, 1939 (Box 14)
    - A Theory of Length and Its Applications to the Calculus of Variations, 1939 (Box 14)
    - On Cauchy's Integral Theorem in the Real Plane, 1939 (Box 14)
    - On Linear Sets in Metric Spaces, 1939 (Box 14)
      With Arthur N. Milgram
    - On Necessary and on Suffieient Conditions in Elementary Mathematics, 1939 (Box 14)
    - On Green's Formula, 1940 (Box 14)
      Includes a presentation draft and a referee's report
    - On Shortest Polygonal Approximations to a Curve, 1940 (Box 14)
    - Redundancies in the Classical Treatment of the Cailehy-Riemann Conditions, 1940 (Box 14)
    - Statistical Metrics, 1942 (Box 14)
    - Differential Equations, 1943 (Box 14)
      Includes drawing of Karl Menger
    - What is Dimension?, 1943 (Box 14)
    - On the Relation Between Calculus of Probability and Statistics, 1944 (Box 14)
    - On the Teaching of Differential Equations, 1944 (Box 14)
    - Projective Generalizations of Metric Geometry, 1944 (Box 14)
    - Tri-Operational Algebra, 1944 (Box 14)
    - Why Study Mathematics?, 1944 (Box 14)
    - Définition intrinsèque de la notion de chemin, 1945 (Box 14)
    - Methods of Presenting e and π, 1945 (Box 14)
    - Analysis without Variables, 1946 (Box 15)
    - General Algebra of Analysis, 1946 (Box 15)
    - General Algebra of Analysis, 1946 (Box 15)
      Includes two copies with comments
    - Aristotelian Demonstration and Postulational Method, 1948 (Box 15)
      With Yves R. Simon, incl. a presentation draft
    - Fundamental and Applied Research in Geometry, 1948 (Box 15)
    - Independent Self-Dual Postulates in Projective Geometry, 1948 (Box 15)
    - Stieltjes Integrals Considered as Lengths, 1948 (Box 15)
    - The Topology of the Triangle Inequality, 1948 (Box 15)
    - Are Variables Necessary in Calculus?, 1949 (Box 15)
    - Generalized Vector Spaces. I. The Structure of Finite-Dimensional Spaces, 1949 (Box 15)
    - La géométrie axiomatique de I' espace projectif, 1949 (Box 15)
    - Modem Geometry and the Theory of Relativity, 1949 (Box 15)
    - Self-Dual Fragments of the Ordinary Plane, 1949 (Box 15)
    - What Paths Have Length?, 1949 (Box 15)
    - The Mathematics of Elementary Thermodynamics, 1950 (Box 15)
    - The Projective Space, 1950 (Box 15)
    - Ensembles flous et fonctions aléatoires, 1951 (Box 15)
      Présentée par M. Arnaud Denjoy
    - Espaces vectoriels généraux, topologies triangulaires, transformations linéaires généralisées, 1951 (Box 15)
    - Probabilistic Geometry, 1951 (Box 15)
    - Probabilistic Theories of Relations, 1951 (Box 15)
    - A Topological Characterization of the Length of Paths, 1952 (Box 15)
    - The Formative Years of Abraham Wald and his Work in Geometry, 1952 (Box 15)
    - Une théorie axiomatique générale des déterminants, 1952 (Box 15)
    - On the Design of Grouping Problems and Related Intelligence Tests, 1953 (Box 15)
    - The Ideas of Variable and Function, 1953 (Box 15)
    - A Simple Definition of Analytic Functions and General Multi-Functions, 1954 (Box 15)
    - Is Calculus a Perfect Tool?, 1954 (Box 15)
    - On Variables in Mathematics and in Natural Science, 1954 (Box 15)
    - The Logic of the Laws of Return. A Study in Meta-Economics, 1954 (Box 15)
    - Tossing a Coin, 1954 (Box 15)
    - Variables de diverses natures, 1954 (Box 15)
    - Die Relativitätstheorie und die Geometrie, 1955 (Box 15)
      Galley Proofreading (1. Fahnenkorrektur)
    - Generalized Derivates and Expansions, 1955 (Box 15)
      With S. S. Shü; incl. draft and copy with comments
    - Random Variables from the Point of View of a General Theory of Variables, 1955 (Box 15)
      Draft
    - The Behavior of a Complex Function at Infinity, 1955 (Box 15)
      Includes Drafts
    - Calculus 1950 - Geometry 1880, 1956 (Box 15)
    - Integrals of Functions and Cumulations of Fluents, 1956 (Box 15)
      Includes rejection letter by journal
    - On the Formulation of Certain Arithmetical Questions, 1956 (Box 15)
      With H. J. Curtis
    - What Are Variables and Constants?, 1956 (Box 15)
    - What Are x and y?, 1956 (Box 15)
    - Why Johnny Hates Math?, 1956 (Box 15)
    - Multiderivatives and Multi-Integrals, 1957 (Box 15)
      Includes draft and two copies with comments
    - How to Find Areas and Slopes Geometrically, 1958 (Box 16)
    - Is w a Function of u?, 1958 (Box 16)
    - New Approach to Teaching Intermediate Mathematics, 1958 (Box 16)
    - Optimal Differences in Computing Probable Derivatives, 1958 (Box 16)
    - Rates of Change and Derivatives, 1958 (Box 16)
    - An Axiomatic Theory of Functions and Fluents, 1959 (Box 16)
    - Gulliver in the Land Without One, Two, Three, 1959 (Box 16)
    - Mensuration and Other Mathematical Connections of Observable Material, 1959 (Box 16)
    - On Probabilistic Metrics and Numerical Metrics with Probability I, 1959 (Box 16)
      With Berthold Schweizer und Abe Sklar
    - A Counterpart of Occam's Razor in Pure and Applied Mathematics. Ontological Uses, 1960 (Box 16)
    - Areas. Numerical Methods, 1960 (Box 16)
    - Gulliver in Applyland, 1960 (Box 16)
    - Gulliver's Return to the Land Without One, Two, Three, 1960 (Box 16)
    - Introduction to: Ernst Mach; The Science of Mechanics, 6th American Edition, 1960 (Box 16)
      Preface; incl. copy with comments
    - Science in Institutes of Technology, 1960 (Box 16)
    - A Counterpart of Occam's Razor in Pure and Applied Mathematics. Semantic Uses, 1961 (Box 16)
    - Eine Algebra der Funktionen, 1961 (Box 16)
    - Frammenti piani autoduali e relative sostituzioni, 1961 (Box 16)
    - The Algebra of Functions: Past, Present, Future, 1961 (Box 16)
    - Variables, Constants, Fluents, 1961 (Box 16)
      Includes drafts
    - What is Length?, 1961 (Box 16)
      With Frank Henmüller
    - A Group in the Substitutive Algebra of the Calculus of Propositions, 1962 (Box 16)
      Includes draft and copy with comments
    - Function Algebra and Propositional Calculus, 1962 (Box 16)
      Includes draft and three copies with comments
    - On Compositive Functions of Matrices, 1962 (Box 16)
    - A Self-Dual Theory of Real Determinants, 1963 (Box 16)
      With Frank Kozin; incl. draft
    - Postulates for the Substitutive Algebra of the 2-Place Functors in the 2-Valued Calculus of Propositions, 1963 (Box 16)
      With Martin Schultz, incl. draft with comment
    - A New Introduction of Analytic Functions and Riemann Surfaces, 1964 (Box 16)
      Includes comments, draft returned from Journal
    - Generalized Martix Inverse, 1964 (Box 16)
    - On Substitutive Algebra and Its Syntax, 1964 (Box 16)
    - Superassociative Systems and Logical Functors, 1964 (Box 16)
    - 600-Jahr-Feier der Wiener Universität, 1965 (Box 16)
      Draft of requested submission to "Die Presse: Unabhängige Zeitung für Österreich." Includes letter requesting Karl Menger write a recollection of his time spent studying there. Also includes a short biography of Menger to accompany the short text.
    - A Characterization of Weierstrass Analytic Functions, 1965 (Box 16)
      Includes commented draft (incomplete)
    - Analytische Funktionen, 1965 (Box 16)
      Includes a longer draft titled "Drei Bermerkungen zu Gedanken von Weierstrass"
    - Une caractérisation des fonctions analytiques, 1965 (Box 16)
      Includes copies with comments
    - Two Theorems on the Generation of System of Functions, 1966 (Box 16)
      With H. Ian Whitlock
    - Weierstrass Analytic Functions, 1966 (Box 16)
      Includes drafts and copy with comments
    - The Role of Uncertainty in Economics, 1967 (Box 16)
    - General Algebraic Equations and Functional Equations, 1968 (Box 16)
    - Mathematical Implications of Mach's ldeas: Positivistic Geometry. Clarification of Functional Connections, 1970 (Box 17)
    - Studies in Geometry, 1970 (Box 17)
      With Leonard M. Blumenthal, Draft Abstract
    - The Geometry Relevant to Modern Education, 1971 (Box 17)
    - The New Foundation of Hyperbolic Geometry, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Bericht über metrische Geometrie, 1972 (Box 17)
    - Österreichischer Marginalismus und mathematische Ökonomie, 1972 (Box 17)
      Includes extract with comments and incomplete draft
    - Austrian Marginalism and Mathematical Economics, 1973 (Box 17)
      Includes incomplete draft
    - Wittgenstein betreffende Seiten aus einem Buch über den Wiener Kreis, 1978 (Box 17)
    - Language and Mathematics, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Introduction to: Hans Hahn; Empiricism, Logic and Mathematics, 1980 (Box 17)
    - On the Origin of the n-Arc Theorem, 1981 (Box 17)
      Includes photograph of Karl Menger
    - Memories of Moritz Schlick, 1982 (Box 17)
    - On Social Groups and Relations, 1983 (Box 17)
    - A Generalization of the Concept of Differentiation and Its Application to Jacobi's Series (and the Taylor's Series), undated (Box 17)
      With S. S. Shü; incl. comments
    - A Generalization of the Concept of Differentiation and Related Topics, undated (Box 17)
      With S. S. Shü; incl. comments and draft
    - A New Approach to Analytical Mechanics, undated (Box 17)
    - A Parameter-Free Introduction of Certain Manifolds / An Introduction of Certain Manifolds Without Assuming Parametrization, undated (Box 17)
      Two titles
    - A Plane Presentation of Complex Functions and Their Composition, undated (Box 17)
      With Appendices by J. and L. Frazin and R. Jindrich, incl. draft
    - A Simple Description of the Projective Plane, undated (Box 17)
    - A Simplification of the Use of Laplace Transforms, Especially in Solving Differential Equations, undated (Box 17)
    - An Estimation of the Rate of a Gaussian Process, undated (Box 17)
      Includes an incomplete copy with comments
    - Analytic Geometries and the New Theory of Variables, undated (Box 17)
      Includes draft with comments
    - Dérivées Partielles Strictes, Paradérivées et les Conditions de Cauchy-Riemann, undated (Box 17)
    - Einige Sätze der Abstrakten Mengenlehre und ihre Anwendungen, undated (Box 17)